So, I'd like to take my students onto a little journey to Stanford
我要带大家去斯坦福溜达一圈
and show them our self-driving car that uses sensors to sense the environment.
展示下使用传感器探测环境的无人驾驶汽车
So let me dive into the class very much right now.
我们开始学习这节课吧
Through our last class,
在上节课
we talked about localization.
我们讨论了定位
We had a robot that lived in an environment and that it could
环境中有个机器人
use its sensors to determine where in the environment it is.
它可以使用传感器确定自己在什么位置
So, here you can see the Google self-driving car using a roadmap localizing itself.
这是一个使用地图定位自己的 Google 无人驾驶汽车
But in addition what's shown here in red are measurements of other vehicles.
除了显示为红色的汽车之外 还有其他车辆的测量值
The car uses lasers and radars to track other vehicles.
汽车使用激光和雷达追踪其他车辆
Today, we're going to talk about how to find other cars.
今天我们将讨论如何查找其他汽车
The reason why we'd like to find other cars is because we wouldn't want to run into them.
查找其他汽车的原因是不想撞到它们
So, we have to understand how to interpret sensor data to make
我们必须了解如何解析传感器数据
assessments not just where these other cars are as in the localization case,
不仅仅要估算这些车在哪 这是定位问题
but also how fast they're moving,
而且要判断车的移动速度
so that we can drive in a way that avoids collisions within the future.
以防止未来出现碰撞现象
That's important not just for cars,
这不仅仅涉及到汽车
it matters for pedestrians and bicyclists and understanding where the cars
而且关系到行人和骑行人士
are and making prediction where they're going to move is absolutely
知道车在哪并预测将移到哪里
essential for safe driving in the Google car potrait.
对于 Google 无人驾驶汽车项目的安全驾驶来说很关键
So in this class, we'll talk about tracking.
在这节课 我们将讨论跟踪
The technique I'd like to teach you is called the Kalman Filter.
我要讲授的技巧叫做卡尔曼滤波器
This is an insanely popular technique for estimating the state of a system.
这是一种非常热门的估算系统状态的技巧
It's actually very similar to the probabilistic localization method we
实际上与我们在之前的课程中讨论的概率定位方法
talked in the previous class, Monte Carlo localization.
非常相似 即蒙特卡罗定位
The primary differences are that Kalman Filters
主要区别是卡尔曼滤波器
estimate a continuous state whereas in Monte Carlo localization,
估算的是连续状态 而在蒙特卡罗定位中
we are forced to chop the word in the discrete places.
我们必须要将环境拆分为离散地点
As a result, the Kalman Filter happens to give us
因此 卡尔曼滤波器可以生成单峰分布
a uni-modal distribution and I'll tell you in a second what that means,
稍后我将介绍单峰分布是什么意思
whereas Monte Carlo was fine with multi-modal distributions.
而蒙特卡罗可以生成多峰分布
Both of these techniques are applicable to
这两种技巧都适用于
robot localization and tracking other vehicles.
机器人定位和跟踪其他车辆
Consider the car down here.
这里有辆车
Let's assume it seizes measurement,
假设它收到了测量值
an object here, here,
这里 这里 和这里有个对象
here, and here for the time is t equals zero,
时间 t 分别等于 0
t equals one, two and three.
等于 1 等于 2 等于 3
Where would you assume the object would be a t equals four?
当 t 等于 4 时 你认为对象会在哪？